I'm Charles Connelly.
This is basic fire safety.
This is smoke detectors.
In this case what we have here is combination detectors.
This is a smoke and carbon monoxide detector.
We recommend that everyone has a smoke detector in their house.
It should be placed in the hallways and other common areas and should be in front of bedroom doors.
Smoke detectors should be at the highest point of the house such as the top of the ceiling.
If you have a hard ceiling, at the very top about 3 feet from the peak.
The reason we put smoke detectors up high is because smoke and heat rises and this is what is going to set the detector off.
Like we said in this case, this is a smoke and carbon monoxide detector.
You can get a carbon monoxide at any Home Depot.
They come in a variety of ways such as ones that can plug into the wall.
Smoke detectors should be checked monthly and every smoke detector has a test button.
In this case, it is towards the back.
In this practice, we are not going to set this one off because we are in an enclosed area and it is very loud.
Batteries should be changed in all smoke detectors twice a year.
It is recommended in good practice to change the batteries when you change your clocks for daylight savings time; once in the Fall and once in the Spring.